A Guide to the Thompson Collection Of Lincolniana 1803-1965
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Thompson Collection of Lincolniana 1803-1965
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 4
1 linear foot
Mr. and Mrs. T. Roger Thompson
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Special Collections and Archives Department by Mr. and Mrs. T. Roger Thompson in May 1974. Supplemented by an additional gift in June 1976.
Biographical/Historical Information
Unknown.
Scope and Content Information
Chiefly articles, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, photographs, and memorabilia, together with scattered correspondence, bills and receipts pertaining to Abraham Lincoln.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The materials are arranged as donated.
Organization
Series I--Nineteenth Century Memorabilia (n.d., 1856,1858-1860, 1863, 1869, 1871, 1892, 1924)
Series II--Photographs (n.d., 1860, 1956, 1964)
Series III--Correspondence (1896, 1927)
Series IV-- Lincoln's Tomb and Statue Ceremonies (1930-1931, 1941)
Series V--Twentieth Century Pamphlets about Lincoln and Illinois (n.d., 1920, 1952-1962)
Series Series VI-- Additional materials (n.d., 1808, 1832, 1865, 1956-1957, 1963)
Contents List
- Series I-Nineteenth Century Memorabilia
  - Six receipted bills for printing and advertising (Box 1)
  - Transcript Office, Dixon, Illinois, to Alexander Gowell and Co. signed John Stevens, publisher December 17, 1856 (Box 1)
  - Dixon Telegraph Bill for subscriptions to Alexander Howell and Co. signed B.B. Shaw (Box 1)
  - Shaw and Beckwith to Alexander Howell and Co. signed Shaw and Beckwith July 1, 1858 (Box 1)
  - Shaw and Beckwith for services to Alexander Howell and Company March 1, 1859 (Box 1)
  - Republican and Telegraph, Power Book and Job Printing Office to Messrs. Signed I.S Boardman per William Parker, Jr. July 24, 1860 (Box 1)
  - Program for Eighth Annual Ball, The Protector Association March 6, 1856 (Box 1)
  - Boston Store, Dixon, Illinois. Auction notice for sale of dry goods June 15, 1859 (Box 1)
  - Notice of Grand Temperance Mass Meeting at the Court House October 25 1869 (Box 1)
  - Lee County Agricultural Society Oct. 3-6 1871 (Box 1)
  - Loyal Publication Society No 59 1963 (Box 1)
  - U.S.A. Temperance Union. Temperance pledge, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Two tickets to National Republican Convention 1892, 1924 (Box 1)
- Series II--Photographs
  - One steel engraving of President Lincoln and his cabinet. (Box 1)
  - Photograph of clay model of Lincoln Statue, with letter. November 12, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Three photographs. Different views of a bust of Lincoln done in classical style. (Box 1)
  - One large post card photograph of Lincoln June 3, 1860 (Box 1)
  - Five Photographs: Lincoln's home, Lincoln's tomb etc. (Box 1)
  - One large framed photograph of Lincoln (Box 1)
  - Framed advertisement of the L and N Railroad showing war map of the Louisville and Nashville RR and connections (Box 1)
- Series III-Correspondence
  - Letter to Frank R. Dixon signed by Noah Brooks, The Ark, Castine Maine February 7, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Letter to the Honorable George C. Dixon, Dixon, Illinois, signed Charles E. Ives, Amboy February 7, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Frank Dixon, McClure Magazine, Mrs. Jefferson Davis January-July 1896 (Box 1)
- Series IV-Lincoln's Tomb and Statue Ceremonies
  - Invitation to attend unveiling of Statue of Lincoln 1930 (Box 1)
  - Invitation from Governor of Illinois to attend a dedication of remodeled tomb of Lincoln 1931 (Box 1)
  - Address of President Hoover at dedication 1931 (Box 1)
  - Tomb of Abraham Lincoln 1941 (Box 1)
  - The Lincoln Tomb, brochure, post card, leaflet (Box 1)
  - News Releases, brochures etc. (Box 1)
  - Invitation to banquet (Box 1)
  - Roger Thompson's press badge (Box 1)
- Series V--Twentieth Century Pamphlets about Lincoln and Illinois
  - Small lapel button advertising Lincoln brand self-rising buckwheat (Box 1)
  - Post card picture of Abraham Lincoln's home, 7 items (Box 1)
  - Small publications about Lincoln and the Lincoln County 1953-1962, 32 items (Box 1)
  - Modern clippings about Lincoln (Box 1)
  - One 1896 clipping about Lincoln (Box 1)
  - Lincoln County, pamphlets 1952-1962 (Box 1)
- Series VI--Additional Materials
  - Catalogues of books about Lincoln and contemporaries (Box 2)
  - T. Roger Thompson items (Box 2)
  - Missouri Gazette, the first newspaper published in Missouri, v. 1 July 26, 1808 (Box 2)
    first known issue in existence
  - Letter from Illinois State Historical Library September 7, 1956 (Box 2)
    discusses authenticity of Missouri Gazette v. 1
  - Four trade cards (Box 2)
  - Two Lincoln heads (Box 2)
  - Lincoln family (Box 2)
  - Lincoln home (Box 2)
  - Photograph and Postcard of statue (Box 2)
  - Lincoln the Soldier 1832 (Box 2)
  - Miami Heraldette (Box 2)
  - Life- What Happened to Lincoln's Body February 15, 1963 (Box 2)
  - New York Herald April 15, 1865, oversized (Box 2)
  - One Framed Photograph of Abraham Lincoln, oversized (Box 2)
  - One framed map, oversized (Box 2)
    War map of Louisville and Nashville Railroad Connections Showing locations of all Battles in the State of Kentucky, Tennessee, Alabama, Georgia with consecutively numbered index